A Guide to the Records of the Division of Motion Picture Censorship, 1926-1968
Library of Virginia
- General correspondence and controversial films, 1922-1966
  - Clark Transfer, Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 53, Folder 84)
  - Cold Wind Against August, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 85)
  - Common Law Wife, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 86)
  - Cool World, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 87)
  - Contempt (see Box 57, Folder 8), 1963 (Box 53, Folder 88)
  - Court (cases in), 1959-1964 (Box 53, Folder 89)
  - Cracked Wedding Bells, 1923 (Box 53, Folder 90)
  - Criticism and comments, 1964-1965 (Box 53, Folder 91)
  - D, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 92)
  - Dead One, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 93)
  - Defiant One (see Kings Go Forth), 1958 (Box 53, Folder 94)
  - Desperate Women, 1954 (Box 53, Folder 95)
  - Devil in the Flesh, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 96)
  - Dillinger, Life of, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 97)
  - Documentary programs, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 98)
  - Domestic Troubles, 1928 (Box 53, Folder 99)
  - E, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 100)
  - Ecstasy, 1939 (Box 53, Folder 101)
  - Elysia, 1958 (Box 53, Folder 102)
  - Exchanges (distributors), 1959-1960 (Box 53, Folder 103)
  - F, 1960-1961 (Box 53, Folder 104)
  - Fast Set, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 105)
  - Film Condition, 1958 (Box 53, Folder 106)
  - Film Daily, 1961-1964 (Box 53, Folder 107)
  - Fire in the Flesh, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 108)
  - Fixing a Stew, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 109)
  - Flesh Merchant, 1956 (Box 53, Folder 110)
  - Fools for Desire, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 111)
  - For Members Only (see Nudist Story), 1963 (Box 53, Folder 112)
  - Fourth Sex, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 113)
  - Frigid Wife, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 114)
  - Fruit is Ripe, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 115)
  - Functions of the Board, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 116)
  - G, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 117)
  - Game of Love, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 118)
  - Garden of Eden, 1958-1960 (Box 53, Folder 119)
  - Girls of the Underworld, 1930 (Box 53, Folder 120)
  - Girls with an Itch, 1958-1959 (Box 53, Folder 121)
  - Goldigging Gentlemen, 1931 (Box 53, Folder 122)
  - Governor of Virginia, 1963 (Box 53, Folder 123)
  - Heads of state agencies, 1963-1964 (Box 53, Folder 124)
  - Heat of the Summer, 1962-1963 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Henry the Ache, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Her Wedding Night, 1954-1962 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - He Who Must Die, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Highway Hell, 1946-1947 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - High Time, 1953-1955 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Hitler Beast of Berlin, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Hollywood Peep Show, 1954-1962 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - House Behind the Cedars, The, 1925 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Human Wreckage, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Husband and Strife, 1924 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - I, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - International Burlesque, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Inventory of furnishing and equipment, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Inspectors, 1958-1968 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Instructions, 1959-1964 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Island in the Sun, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Island of Lost Souls, 1932-1933 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Isle of Love, 1922 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Is Your Daughter Safe?, 1927-1928 (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - I Spit on Your Grave, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - It's Hot in Paradise, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 22)
  - J, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 23)
  - K, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 24)
  - Karamoja, 1954-1964 (Box 54, Folder 25)
  - Keeler Affair, 1964-1965 (Box 54, Folder 26)
  - Kings Go Forth, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 27)
  - L, 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 28)
  - Lady Chatterly, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 29)
  - LaParisienne, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 30)
  - La Ronde, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 31)
  - Last Man on Earth, 1924 (Box 54, Folder 32)
  - Latuko, 1952 (Box 54, Folder 33)
  - Lecture Reel, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 34)
  - Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 35)
  - Lovers, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 36)
  - Lovers of Paris, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 37)
  - Love Mart, 1928 (Box 54, Folder 38)
  - M, 1960-1963 (Box 54, Folder 39)
  - Mad Youth, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 40)
  - Main Street Girl, 1947 (Box 54, Folder 41)
  - Magdalena, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 42)
  - Make Mine a Double, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 43)
  - Manager's Letters, 1958-1959 (Box 54, Folder 44)
  - Many a Slip, 1931 (Box 54, Folder 45)
  - Mating Urge, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 46)
  - Max Baer vs. Joe Louis, 1935 (Box 54, Folder 47)
  - Merry Ways of Gay Way or Hollywood Peep Show, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 48)
  - Midnight Frolics, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 49)
  - Minutes of censor meetings, 1942 (Box 54, Folder 50)
  - Miracle of Birth, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 51)
  - Miracle of Life, 1926 (Box 54, Folder 52)
  - Misty, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 53)
  - Molesters, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 54)
  - Mom and Dad, 1948-1949 (Box 54, Folder 55)
  - Moon is Blue, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 56)
  - Motherhood, 1938 (Box 54, Folder 57)
  - Morals Squad, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 58)
  - Mr. Adam, 1933 (Box 54, Folder 59)
  - Murders in the Museum, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 60)
  - My Baby is Black, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 61)
  - N, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 62)
  - NAACP, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 63)
  - Nana, 1957-1958 (Box 54, Folder 64)
  - Nature Girl and the Slaver, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 65)
  - New Aunt, The, 1929 (Box 54, Folder 66)
  - Night, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 67)
  - No Sun in Venice, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 68)
  - Nudist Story, The, 1961-1965 (Box 54, Folder 69)
  - O, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 70)
  - Order in the Court, 1934-1935 (Box 54, Folder 71)
  - Official Action of the Board, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 72)
  - One Summer of Happiness, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 73)
  - Only for Love, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 74)
  - O MI Gosh, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 75)
  - Orgy at Lil's Place, 1964-1965 (Box 54, Folder 76)
  - P, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 77)
  - Pace that Kills, 1929-1941 (Box 54, Folder 78)
  - Parking, 1961-1963 (Box 54, Folder 79)
  - Penny a Peep, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 80)
  - Picking Peaches, 1924-1925 (Box 54, Folder 81)
  - Pleasure Lovers, 1964-1965 (Box 54, Folder 82)
  - Police, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 83)
  - Primrose Path (Flaming Passion), 1930-1933 (Box 54, Folder 84)
  - Private Property, 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 85)
  - Procedures, 1959-1964 (Box 54, Folder 86)
  - Q, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 87)
  - R, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 88)
  - Race Suicide, 1938 (Box 54, Folder 89)
  - Railway Express Co., 1963 (Box 54, Folder 90)
  - Rape of the Innocent, 1951-1953 (Box 54, Folder 91)
  - Rebel with a Cause, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 92)
  - Records retention, 1949-1966 (Box 54, Folder 93)
  - Rejections (Aug. 1-Aug. 1), 1922-1952 (Box 54, Folder 94)
  - Rejections (July 1-June 30), 1953-1958 (Box 54, Folder 95)
  - Rejections (July 1-Apr. 1), 1959-1965 (Box 54, Folder 96)
  - Requests for information on censorship, 1961-1964 (Box 54, Folder 97)
  - Respectful Tramp, 1959-1961 (Box 54, Folder 98)
  - Revoking of licenses issued, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 99)
  - Ritual of Love, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 100)
  - Road to Ruin, 1937 (Box 54, Folder 101)
  - Roanoke Times, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 102)
  - Room at the Top (see Box 57, Folder 9, for transcript), 1959 (Box 54, Folder 103)
  - Rope, The, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 104)
  - Rotation of Board Members, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 105)
  - Routine Work, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 106)
  - S, 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 107)
  - Savage Eye, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 108)
  - Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 109)
  - Sex, The Drama of Life, 1932 (Box 54, Folder 110)
  - Shame, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 111)
  - She Done Him Wrong, 1933-1935 (Box 54, Folder 112)
  - She Should Have Stayed in Bed, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 113)
  - She Walks by Night, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 114)
  - Should a Girl Marry?, 1929 (Box 54, Folder 115)
  - Sin and Desire, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 116)
  - Sin of the Fathers, 1949-1952 (Box 54, Folder 117)
  - Sin You Sinners, 1963-1964 (Box 54, Folder 118)
  - Sinister's Urge, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 119)
  - Slaves in Bondage, 1938-1941 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Snow was Black, The, 1957-1958 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Some Wild Oats, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Son of Satan, A, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Souls in Pawn, 1941 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Syphilis, 1938 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Street Corner, 1951-1965 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Street of Shame, 1957-1960 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Story of Bob and Sally, The, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Supplies, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Supreme Court's rulings on films, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - T, 1960-1961 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Teenage Bride, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Tell Your Children, 1941 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Temptation, 1962-1964 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Test Tube Babies, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Theaters, 1964-1965 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Those College Girls, 1923-1938 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Three Women, 1924 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Time of Desire, The, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - Tomorrow's Children, 1941 (Box 55, Folder 21)
  - Traveling Light, 1963-1964 (Box 55, Folder 22)
  - Truth, The, 1961-1962 (Box 55, Folder 23)
  - U, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 24)
  - Ugetsu, 1955 (Box 55, Folder 25)
  - Unguarded Girls, 1930-1931 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Unnatural Birth, 1958 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Unshamed, 1939 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Unwelcome Children, 1929 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Veiled Aristocrats, 1932 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Victoria Films (see Traveling Light), 1963 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Virgin Spring, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1952-1957 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Virginia State Board of Censors, 1922-1947 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - W, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Wages of Sin, 1932-1939 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Wasted Lives, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Weekend, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Wheeler Films, 1962-1965 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Weird Lovemakers, 1964 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Well, The, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - White Cargo, 1930-1939 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Witch, The, 1957-1958 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - World Without Shame, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - W, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 10)
- Censorship Reports, 1960-1965
  This series documents the work of censorship boards in other states and Canada. The format of the reports vary, however all reports provide movie titles, scenes deleted from movies, total number of prints, and the studio responsible for producing the film.
  Arranged chronologically by date of report.
  - Censorship Report (Kansas), 1962-1964 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Censorship Report (New York), 1963 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Censorship Report (New York), 1964 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Censorship Report (New York), 1965 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Censorship Report (Toronto, Ontario), 1960-1962 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Censorship Report (Toronto, Ontario), 1963-1965 (Box 57, Folder 6)
- Correspondence and Controversial Films - Transcripts, 1922-1966
  - Transcript - Band of Angels, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Transcript - Contempt, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Transcript - Room at the Top, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Transcript - Street of Shame, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Transcript - The Story of Bob and Sally, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 11)